(ペイン)伝説の三忍
自来也も ついに死す。
One of the legendary Sannin...
Jiraiya is no more...
我らに この秘密がなければ
勝てはしなかっただろうな。
If we didn't have this secret,
we could not have won.
(ペイン)さすがは我が師と
讃えておこう。
Let us praise him as our teacher.
ところで… そろそろ出てこい。
By the way...
you can come out.
(ゼツ)かなり かかったね。
Sure took you a while.
His opponent was Jiraiya,
after all.
相手は
あの自来也だったのだからな。
とんだ邪魔が入った。
That was some interference we got.
マダラから 九尾を狩るように
命を受けていたんだがな。
I'm under orders from Madara
to capture the Nine-Tails.
それじゃあさ 九尾を狩るのを
見てみたいから一緒に行こうよ。
Well then... I'd love to see
the Nine-Tails captured,
so let's go together.
ダメだ。 オレは 別の戦いを見にいく。
No! I'm going to watch another battle.
え～っ…。
うるさい 黙れ。
- What?
- Shut up!
(ゼツ)どの戦いを見んの？
Which battle is that?
(ゼツ)それは…。
The battle between...
(水月)大丈夫かね？ サスケのヤツ。
I wonder if Sasuke is okay...
(香燐)何がだ？
What do you mean?
What if the first Akatsuki hideout
is a bull's-eye?
暁のアジト探索 １発目が
ビンゴだったらって話さ。
(重吾)イタチが このアジトに
いるとでも言うのか？
Are you saying Itachi is
inside this hideout?
I said, "what if?"
(水月)さあね。 いたらって話。
相当なやり手なんだろ？ イタチって。
This Itachi is supposed to
be really strong, right?
サスケにかぎって
やられるなんてこと あるわけ…。
There's no way that Sasuke
could lose to...
オレたちも まさかのときのこと
考えたほうがいいのかもね。
Maybe we should be thinking about
a worst-case scenario.
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...
ウチは ここから中の様子を探る。
何かあったら すぐに向かうぞ。
I'm going to check out
the inside from here.
If anything happens, we're going in!
はあ？ 何 急に
仕切りだしちゃってんの？
Huh? Why're you taking over
all of a sudden?
キミは サスケのこととなると
すぐ ムキになる。
When it comes to Sasuke,
you go overboard.
べ… 別に ウチは ムキになど…
やっ… やんのか！ このヤロウ！
Th-That's not true...!
I'm not going... You idiot!
なら オレは 鳥たちに頼んで➡
Then I'll ask the birds to
scour the area
周囲から敵が追ってこないか
見張らせておこう。
and look out for
the enemy's approach.
Geez... Both of you...
ったく どいつもコイツも…。
《マジメだねぇ…》
They're so diligent.
(ナルト)こっちも ニセモノだってばよ。
This one's a fake too...
サスケのニオイを
追っかけてるはずなのに…。
I'm chasing after Sasuke's scent, yet...
敵が 一枚上手ってことか。
It seems the enemy is
one step ahead of us.
だから 敵の陽動以上に
数で対抗してんだろうが。
That's why we're compensating
for their diversions with numbers!
こっちは あらかた調べつくした。
We've checked this side thoroughly.
いったん 本体に戻って
情報を渡したほうがいいかもな。
We should report this to the original.
(カカシ)どうした？ ナルト。
What's wrong, Naruto?
The south forest only had dummies.
南の森には ダミーしか
いなかったみてえだ。
そうか。
I see.
(キバ)なに落ち込んでんだ？
Why so depressed?!
You never give up.
Isn't that your ninja way?!
あきらめねえのが
テメエの忍道じゃなかったのかよ？
(サクラ)そうよ ナルト。
He's right, Naruto!
よっしゃ!!
All right!
I'll use the chakra I've restored
to increase the Shadow Clones.
回復したチャクラの分だけ
さらに影分身を増やしていくぞ！
みんな 頼んだぜ。
I'm counting on you all!
任せとけって！
- Leave it to us!
(イタチ)来たか。
So you've come...
(サスケ)誰だ？
Who's there?!
It's me... Sasuke.
(イタチ)オレだ… サスケ。
少し背が伸びたか？
You've grown a bit taller.
And you're still the same.
Even those cold eyes...
アンタは 相変わらずだな。
その冷たい目も。
前のように 大声で がむしゃらに
突っ込んではこないか。
Not going to scream and attack
like you did before?
It's just as you said...
アンタの言ったとおり
アンタを恨み 憎み➡
I've hated you... and resented you...
そして アンタを
殺すためだけにオレは…。
for the singular purpose
of killing you, I...
I...
オレは…。
have lived my life!
生きてきた！
千鳥？
Chidori?
アンタを殺す！
I will kill you!
うお～っ！
(死ね！))
Die!
フン。 アンタはオレのことを
何もわかっちゃいない。
You don't know a thing about me...
How much hatred I carry inside me...
どれほどの憎しみを
心のなかに抱えているか。
そのおかげで
どれほど強くなっているか。
And how strong I have become
because of that hatred.
アンタは オレのことを
何もわかっちゃいない。
You don't know me at all.
強くなったな。
You've become... strong.
Come to the Uchiha hideout alone.
１人でうちはのアジトに来い。
そこで決着をつけさせてやろう。
I'll let you settle things there.
Sasuke!
(水月)サスケ！
命令があるまで
動くなと言ったはずだぞ。
I told you not to move until
you received orders.
香燐が 他のチャクラを感じたって
言ったから 気になってね。
Karin said she sensed another chakra,
so we were worried.
Feathers?
羽根？
オレについて来い。 行くぞ。
Follow me. Let's go!
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
Banquet Invitation
(トビ)いい流れだ。
あとは 次の脱皮でヘビのままか➡
He's coming along nicely. Now...
Will you still emerge as a snake?
Or will you transform into a hawk?
それとも タカに変わるか見ものだ。
We shall see, Sasuke...
サスケ。
同じチャクラがあちこちにあるぞ。
The same chakra is all over the place!
どうなってんだ？
What's going on?!
進路を変えるかい？ サスケ。
Should we change course, Sasuke?
気にするな。 真っ直ぐに突っ切る。
Ignore it. We'll forge straight ahead.
よかった。 遠回りは疲れる。
Good. Taking the long way
would've been tiring.
サスケ！
Sasuke!
What was that?!
なに？ 今の。
影分身だよ！
A Shadow Clone.
ナルトか。
Naruto, eh?
《うっとうしいヤツだ》
What a pest.
多重影分身。 なるほど。
Multi-Shadow Clones... I get it now...
あちこちにいる
同じチャクラの正体は今のヤツか。
The same chakra I sense all over
the place belongs to him.
見つけた！
Found him!
よくやったぜ！ どっちだ？
Good job!
Which way?!
こっちだ！
This way!
《もう逃がさねえぞ サスケ！》
I'm not letting you get away
this time, Sasuke!
これは？ すごいチャクラ！
What is this?!
A humongous chakra!
And it's fast! Incoming!!
それに 速い。 くる！
アンタは…。
You're...!
Only Sasuke-kun may go beyond this point.
(鬼鮫)ここからは
サスケ君一人で行ってください。
イタチさんの命令でしてね。
It's Itachi-san's orders.
他の方々は ここで
待っていてもらいましょうか。
The rest of you are welcome
to wait here.
わかった。 小隊で動いていたのは
もともと➡
All right. Besides, we were only
traveling as a platoon
in order to prevent interference
for my showdown...
１対１に邪魔が
入らないようにするためだからな。
ちょうどいい。
サスケ！
This will do.
No, you can't, Sasuke!
それはダメだ。 コイツを倒して
全員で行くんだ！
Let's take him down and
go in together!
私は 戦う気などありませんがね。
I have no intention of fighting.
But if you insist on going with him,
I will show no mercy.
無理やり通るというなら
容赦しませんよ。
香燐 おとなしくしていろ。
これは オレの復讐だ。
Karin... Stay put.
This is my  vendetta.
チッ…。
干柿鬼鮫… そして 大刀 鮫肌。
Hoshigaki Kisame...
And the Great Shark Skin Sword...
Hmm?
Have you forgotten me?
忘れたか？ 鬼灯満月の弟
鬼灯水月だよ。
I'm Suigetsu Hozuki,
the younger bother of Mangetsu Hozuki.
おぉ… 見違えましたよ。
大きくなりましたね 水月。
Oh... I didn't recognize you!
You've grown, Suigetsu.
ここで ただ サスケの帰りを
待つのもなんだから➡
I don't want to just wait around
for Sasuke...
ヒマつぶしに
楽しく遊んでもらえないかな？
Will you let me kill some time
and have some fun with you,
Kisame-senpai?!
鬼鮫先輩。
お兄さんと違い
やんちゃですねぇ…。
Unlike your brother,
you're quite cocky, aren't you?
少し 削ってあげましょう。
Maybe I should grind you down a bit.
水月！ サスケの言いつけを
守らなくていいのか？
Suigetsu... Shouldn't we abide
by Sasuke's orders?
《のんきなこと
言ってんじゃないよ！
Don't be stupid! You blockhead!
この でくの坊が！》
みんな！ こっちだってばよ！
This way, guys!
(ヒナタ)待って ナルト君！
Wait! Naruto-kun...
《このチャクラは！》
This chakra...
どうも～！
Howdy!
どわっ！ なんだ!?
What the-?!
ハハハハ！ いやいや…
どうもどうも どうもっす！
Well now... How's it going there,
there, and there?
こんなところで
木ノ葉の皆さんに ばったり！
Imagine running into the Hidden Leaf
in a place like this...
しかも… 二の四の六の…
８対１とは間の悪い。 ハハハハ！
I mean... It's two, four, six...
Eight against one. Such bad timing.
(ヤマト)その衣…
お前も 暁のメンバーだな。
That robe...
You're a member of the Akatsuki!
(カカシ)コイツは カブトの残した
暁のリストには載ってなかったが…。
Though he wasn't on the list
that Kabuto left us.
アハ！ 新人なもんで。
どうもよろしく。
(赤丸)ワン！ ワン！
Oh, I'm a newbie. Nice to meet you.
(キバ)ヘッ！ ふざけやがって。
余裕かましてんじゃねぇ！
Hah! Think you're funny?!
Don't waste our time!
うかつな動きはするな。
まずは 様子を見る。
Don't be rash. Study the situation first.
数は 圧倒的に
こちらが有利なんだからな。
Right now, we have him outnumbered.
あらら… ナメられちゃってます？
ボクのこと。
Oh dear...
Am I being underestimated?
By you guys?
《シノ : これが 暁か…》
So this is an Akatsuki member...
《サクラ : また 変なのが！
Another weirdo...
サスケ君を目の前にして
こう何度も 何度も…》
They keep getting between us and
Sasuke-kun over and over again!
ん？
邪魔すんじゃねぇ！
Don't get in our way!
影分身！
A Shadow Clone?!
うわ～っ！
おわっ！
な～んてね。
Just kidding...
でやぁ～っ！
はぁっ！
あの小僧よりは マシに
その大刀を扱うようですね。
It seems you're more proficient
with the blade than that kid.
小僧!?
Kid?!
再不斬先輩のことか!?
You mean, Zabuza-senpai?
元来 私の大刀 鮫肌は
斬り合う道具ではないんですがね。
My Great Shark Skin Sword was
never intended for dueling, you know!
そりゃ こっちも同じ！
斬るんじゃなくて…。
Same here. This one's...
断つのさ！
for killing!
チッ！ 何が 楽しく遊ぶ だ！
本気で殺し合ってるじゃないか！
Tsk! Have fun? As if!
They're dead serious!
おい 重吾！ お前からも…。
Hey! Jugo... Tell him...
大丈夫。 ２人の戦いの邪魔を
するヤツは 近くにいないって➡
It's okay... The birds are telling me
小鳥たちも言ってる。
there's no one nearby who will interfere
with their fighting.
《まったく…。
仲間が こんな調子で➡
Geez... What if something happens
to Sasuke
サスケに もしものことがあったら…。
while these idiots are going at it?
木ノ葉だって
追ってきてるっていうのに…。
Even the Hidden Leaf are in pursuit!
木ノ葉の動きが止まった？》
The Hidden Leaf have stopped?
(トビ)図に乗りすぎでしょう！
You're so full of yourself!
キミみたいな子に
何ができるってのかな!?
Just what can a kid like you do?!
ナルト君…。
《よかった…》
Naruto-kun...
ヒナタ！ ナルトなら あれくらい大丈夫。
Thank goodness...
Hinata!
Naruto can handle the damage!
敵から 目をそらさないで。
Don't take your eyes off the enemy!
ありゃりゃ？
Hmm? Are you guys analyzing
my strength right now?
もしかして ボクの力量とか
観察されちゃったりしてとか？
木ノ葉の皆さんは抜け目ないな！
The Hidden Leaf are very shrewd...
でも 新人にしちゃ
やるほうでしょ？ ボクも。 ウフフフ！
But for a newbie, I'm pretty good...
don't you think?
ナルトの攻撃は
すべて スカされてますね。
He's dodged every one
of Naruto's attacks.
遊ばれてるね。 何が目的だ？
He's toying with us.
But what is he after?
《チッ！ 大刀を操るパワーは
ヤツのが ちょっと上か》
Tsk! He has a tad more power
in wielding the blade.
なら！
Well then...!
一本調子ですね。
Such a monotone effort.
再不斬より上だと言ったのは
取り消しますよ。
I take back what I said about you
being better than Zabuza.
くらえ!!
Eat this!
今のは惜しかったでしょ？ 先輩！
Almost got you there, didn't I?
何を はしゃいでるんです？
What are you so excited about?
Is it your snack time?
そろそろ
おやつの時間じゃないのですか？
何を！
What?!
《チャクラが… ここまで消耗するほど
使っていないはずなのに！》
My chakra...
But I didn't use up that much yet!
私の鮫肌は チャクラを削り食らう…。
My Shark Skin Sword grinds
and absorbs chakra.
もっと
賢いかと思っていましたが…。
I thought you would be more observant.
もう一度 試してみますか？
Care for another taste?
くっ！ コイツ…。
Why you...!
さてと… 何して遊びましょうか？
木ノ葉の皆さん！
Now then... What shall we play,
Hidden Leaf folks?
テメエなんかと遊んでる暇はねえ！
そのとおり。
We don't have time to waste
on the likes of you!
なぜなら サスケを
さっさと追わなければならない。
He's right!
That's because we have to go
after Sasuke.
ワン ワン！
シノ！ お前は 前回のサスケ奪還任務は
不参加だったからな。
Shino, you didn't get to go on
the last mission to retrieve Sasuke!
今回は頼むぜ！
We're counting on you this time!
《サイ : 繋がり か…》
Our bond, is it?
よし みんな！
さっさと終わらせよう。
All right... everyone.
Let's end this quickly.
フォーメーションＢでいくよ みんな！
We'll go with Formation B, everyone.
オッス！
Roger!
(キバ)おう！
(ヒナタ)はい！
- Right!
- Yes sir!
なんだか 本気モードっすね！
こっちも 気合い 入れなくっちゃ。
Ohh? Seems you're serious.
Well, I'd better get fired up.
野郎！ ふざけやがって!!
You jerk... Quit kidding around!
ナルト！ 今は フォーメーションに集中して。
あぁ わかってる！
Naruto, concentrate on the formation!
Yeah, I know.
いくわよ。 キバ！ そっちも オーケー？
Let's do it.
Kiba, are you ready on your side?
いつでも いいぜ！ なぁ？ 赤丸。
ワン！
Anytime. Right, Akamaru?!
それじゃ いくわよ。
Then here goes!
しゃ～！ んなろ～!!
ありゃ～！
こりゃ また ずいぶん高く…。
Oh my, so high...
That girl has such brute power.
とんだ怪力少女！
ゲッ！ おとりに気をとられてる隙に
３人で囲むつもり!?
Oops! They distracted me with the decoy...
And now those three are surrounding me!
これじゃ どれをかわしたらいいか
わからないよ！
I don't know which one to dodge!
ちょ ちょ… ちょっと
それって ずるいでしょ！
S-Say, that's no fair!
よそ見してる暇はねえ！
ワン ワン！
- No time for you to look!
- Oh dear...
なんと！
What...?
しゃ～！ た～っ!!
オレ！
Shannaro! Shannaro!
Olay!
３対１だなんて 木ノ葉の卑怯者！
螺旋丸!!
Three against one?!
You Hidden Leaf cowards!
ギョ ギョ ギョッ！
おとりじゃなかったの!?
Rasengan!
You weren't the decoy?
やられ…。
You got me...!
なっ！
てない！
Not!
忍法 通せんぼの術！
Ninja Art! Blockade Jutsu!
まったく… みんなで やるなんて
言っちゃって。
Cripes... You said you were going
to do it all together...
信じちゃったじゃないですか！
And I believed you!
みんな 止まるな！
散り散りになって 強行突破だ。
Don't stop, everyone!
Separate and force your way through!
あちゃ～！
に… 忍法… え～っと… もう!!
Oh dear! N-Ninja Art...
Umm... Geez!
なんだ？ この術は…。
What kind of jutsu is that?
あっ！ ひらめいた!!
I got it! I'm going to name this jutsu...
この術は 忍法 モグラたたきの術と
名づけよう！
Ninja Art: Whack-A-Mole Jutsu!
たたく側と たたかれる側が
逆だけどね…。
Except the roles for hitting are reversed...
先輩。
あぁ コイツは マジで倒していかないと
先に進ませてくれないようだね。
Senpai...
I know...
Unless we finish him off for good,
he won't let us move forward.
クソ！
Damn it!
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 次は何して遊ぶ？
Say say... What shall we play next?
こんな所で 足止め
くらってる場合じゃねえんだ！
We can't be wasting time
in a place like this!
あぁ わかっている。
次は 戦闘フォーメーションＡでいくよ。
I know that.
We'll go with Battle Formation A next.
《もう少しだ…。
Just a bit longer...
You just wait, Itachi!
待ってろ イタチ！》
you are next to me
omae ga tonari ni iru
you are laughing
omae ga waratte iru
you seem so happy
omae ga ureshisou de
so I laughed too
ore mo waratta
you were so innocent and naive
omae wa mujaki datta
you were so kindhearted
omae wa yasashi katta
you sometimes cried
omae wa tokidoki naki
so I was troubled
ore wa komatta
who did I ask strength from at that time
dare yori tsuyosa wo motometa ano koro
since that was my one and only weakness
ore no tatta hitotsu no yowasa ga
that was you
omae datta
and it was you
omae datta n da
I want to see you
aitai
overnights
yoru wo koete
over time
toki wo koete
I want to see you now
ima aitai
い… いらっしゃいませ。
パーティーにようこそ。
Next Episode
My foolish younger brother...
まもなく 始まりますので
こちらへどうぞ。
So you've finally arrived before me.
(ヤマト)ただ今より 350回突破を
記念いたしまして…。
It seems you've been waiting
for this moment...
ちょっと待った～！
But the same goes for me.
何やってんだってばよ！
主人公のオレが呼ばれてないって
どういうこった!?
Come...!
Recreate my death as you've seen it.
だって キミ
350話に出てなかったから。
それは たまたま…。
あれ!? そうだったっけ？
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Longest Moment..."
ナルトは 100話と300話にも
出演していなかったはず。
The Longest Moment...
How far do you see ahead?
うっせぇ！ 252話から登場した
新参者のお前に言われたかねえや。
主人公ってわりには
キリ番に縁がねえよな。
"COMMEMORATING THE 350TH EPISODE"
W-Welcome to the party.
影が薄いんじゃないのか？
お前が言うな！
It will begin shortly,
so please come this way.
In commemoration of passing
the 350th episode...
でも キリ番に出番なしなんて
主人公失格ね。
Hold it!
サクラちゃんまで そんな…。
What are... you doing?!
それでは 乾杯！
(みんな)乾杯！
Why didn't you guys invite me,
the main character?!
Well, you weren't in Episode 350.
チクショウ…。
(ヒナタ)ナルト君。
Th-That was just by coincidence...
Huh? Really?
ド… ドンマイ！
You weren't in Episode 100
or Episode 300 either.
なぐさめになってねえってばよ…。
Shut up! I don't want to be told
by a newcomer like you
who started from Episode 252!
(ハデス)『FAIRY TAIL』 前回までは…。
(ナツ)お～し！ いよいよ
最終決戦ってとこだな。
For a main character,
you don't seem to have much luck
with milestone episodes.
(ハッピー)オイラ 魚は好きだけど
犬は苦手なんだ。
Maybe you're not so popular?
はあ？ なんだ？ いきなり…。
I don't want to be told by you!
リリーは 苦手なものってあるの？
あるよね？
But having no lines in
a milestone episode is pretty sad
for a main character.
(パンサーリリー)そんなものは ない。
ないったら ない!!
Not you too, Sakura-chan...
(ハッピー)あやしい…。
So here's a toast! Cheers!
- Cheers! Congratulations!
- Damn it!
N-Naruto-kun...
Ch-Cheer up!
You're not helping me here...